A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, RG 2, 1981-1990 FA402
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, RG 2, 1981-1990
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA402
4.38 Cubic Feet 330 35mm microfilm reels.
330 Reels 330 microfilm reels (35mm)
Scope and Contents note
Rockefeller Foundation general correspondence:
Correspondence of The Rockefeller Foundation consists principally of material not directly connected with an institutional grant. It includes inter-office memoranda, correspondence between field officers and the home office; extracts from officers' diaries; forms and other material relating to fellowships; casual requests for information, employment, or aid; printed matter; and letters of abuse received by the Foundation. As such, the General Correspondence provides insight into the day-to-day workings of the Foundation.
Programs other than public health are not amply represented in the early portion of the General Correspondence. Material on the Division of Humanities and the Division of Social Sciences is especially scanty before 1935. After 1940, the volume of this material increases steadily. Indeed, the General Correspondence files as a whole are relatively compact up to 1940; after 1941, they expand enormously.
Some of the most important features and subjects of these files are as follows:
100: STAFF COMMUNICATIONS AND INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS
This designation applies to two distinct types of documents.
(1) STAFF COMMUNICATIONS. Much of the material under this heading consists of correspondence between or regarding staff officers (eg. a field officer and a member of the home office staff), or gives details of employment and assignment of the field officer. Thus this file is in the nature of a supplement of the Foundation's personnel records. Correspondence between retirees and active staff members is often also filed under this designation, under the names of the individuals. One will also find here inter-office correspondence from the New York headquarters. Of special interest in this connection are the memos of Raymond B. Fosdick (President of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1936-1948), which usually consist of several folders for each year indicated. Some correspondence with trustees, especially Thomas B. Debevoise, may also be found here.
(2) INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS. Correspondence between The Rockefeller Foundation and the League of Nations (especially with Arthur Sweetser) lodges under this heading and persists into the 1940s. After the establishment of the United Nations Organization in 1944/5, documentation of the Foundation's cooperation with various U.N. efforts is to be found. Of special interest are the files regarding Selskar M. Gunn and Warren Weaver's service with UNRRA (1944-1946) and John Marshall's presence as an observer at the earliest organizational meetings of UNESCO (1946-1947).
200: THE UNITED STATES (201-258: Individual States and Territories)
The largest concentration of material is to be found under this designation. It is also the most miscellaneous in character. Correspondence ranges from communications with Federal agencies and departments, to letters of advice, records of interviews, appeals for aid, employment inquiries, and crank mail.
The vast bulk of these files dating between 1927 and 1939 relates to the work of the International Health Division, supplementing material previously processed as RG 5. This includes material on grants to state boards of health, training grants for public health personnel at stations in Ohio or Mississippi, and advice on administrative matters. Following the practice of the IHD, most of these earlier files were arranged under an individual state heading rather than under that of the nation as a whole. By 1935 most of the IHD activities had declined as funding became available to the states through the Federal government for this purpose. Correspondence with the individual state agencies shrank accordingly. The advisory functions of the IHD thereafter took place mainly in the form of pooling information (and occasionally personnel) with the U.S. Public Health Service.
Those states files which remain sizeable after 1935 (such as 216: Illinois-University of Chicago, and 248: Tennessee: TVA) do not relate primarily to IHD activities. In 1951, the use of state numbers in filing was almost totally abandoned.
200: UNITED STATES PUBLIC HEALTH SERVICE
During World War II, the Foundation maintained close ties with USPHS, as reflected in the large file of correspondence between Foundation officers and various USPHS officials. This file refers particularly to the Foundation's effort to provide yellow fever vaccine to the Armed Forces. Also of interest for this period is a set of weekly reports on the incidence of virulent disease (plague, smallpox, etc.) around the world.
200E: FELLOWSHIPS
The earlier portion of material so designated (through 1935) is taken up with grants for training public health personnel as requested by various state boards of health. It thus amplifies the documentation of IHD activities noted above. This material includes both declinations as well as acceptances.
Similar material through the 1930s is to be found under 200S: Social Science Research Council, consisting mostly of application forms and correspondence concerning potential SSRC grantees.
For the years 1945-46, an extensive file of Postwar Fellowships follows the regular fellowship file in the General Correspondence. While the character of Foundation support of these Fellows is unclear, the advisory function of Foundation officers in their selection and placement is amply documented here.
300-833: INDIVIDUAL NATIONAL FILES
The files under this heading include administrative and budgetary material for field offices, reports of interviews with potential grantees, governmental and educational figures, diary extracts (usually travel notes, sometimes quite extensive), and miscellaneous correspondence with private and public scientific or cultural institutions and individuals. The majority of this material (especially before 1935) continues the records of the IHD in its international program (see RG 5), and deals primarily with public health programs and medical training. After 1935, the subject matter in the files becomes more diversified.
Scattered throughout these series are observations by Foundation officers on the political and social climate around the world. The Rockefeller Foundation maintained political neutrality regarding the internal affairs of host countries, and cooperated closely with governmental ministries and state-controlled universities -- especially in the areas of public health and the social sciences. Nevertheless, a close watch was kept on developments affecting intellectual freedom and the general climate of cooperation which the Foundation saw as the main prerequisite for performing or sponsoring significant work. This is reflected in the General Correspondence files, where one may find contemporary eyewitness reports and informed outside opinions on such phenomena of this century as the development of Fascism in Europe, the growth of Communism in eastern Europe and China, and the rise or fall of various dictatorships in Latin America.
Large quantities of material may be found under the following headings:
300: South America 315: Cuba 400: Great Britain 427: Canada 437: Jamaica 464: India (including 464.1: Mysore and 464.5: Travancore, through 1944) 500: France 601: China 700: Europe
The bulk of these files indicates either high levels of Foundation activity or the presence of a field office in the country concerned, and thus an "Administration" file will be found here as well as material filed alphabetically or under a program letter. Special features include the 1945-46, 500E file (France-Government Fellowships), which consist of material similar to that described under 200E for the same period. Under 700, one will also find material on the Paris Field Office supplementing that processed separately as RG 6.1.
SPECIAL TOPIC: REFUGEE SCHOLARS, 1933-1946
The General Correspondence contains a mass of material on the plight of European scholars deprived of means or work by the rise of Fascism. This material is similar and supplementary to that found in RG 1 under the same heading. Most of the material in the General Correspondence bearing on this topic may be found as listed below:
717: Germany--Refugee Scholars, 1933-1939 789: Poland-----Refugee Scholars, 1936-1939 200: U.S.---------Refugee Scholars, 1940-1945
These files generally fall into two parts:
(1) A chronological file entitled "Exiled Scholars" which consists of officer's correspondence, diary extracts, lists of exiled academics compiled from various sources, correspondence with various committees and institutions engaged in placing these scholars, and copies of the minutes of those committees with which The Rockefeller Foundation cooperated most closely.
(2) An alphabetical file of correspondence with or concerning individual scholars whose placement the Foundation sponsored or financed in part.
(3) Much material filed under 700: Europe and individual European country numbers (including 400: Great Britain, and 805: Turkey) during the period 1933-1945 also deals with this topic.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Archival records have been reformatted to microfilm. User copies of the microfilm are available for research.
Fascism; Fascism -- Europe; Dictatorship -- Latin America; Europe; South America; United States; Refugees; Social sciences; Yellow fever -- Vaccination; Philanthropy -- United States; Viruses -- Research; Yellow fever; Refugee Scholars -- Germany; Great Britain; Philanthropy; Humanities; Arts; France; Life sciences; Medical education; India; Jamaica; Communism -- Europe, Eastern; Communism; Dictatorship; Cuba; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Canada; China; Charities; Refugee Scholars -- United States; Refugee Scholars -- World War II; Medical sciences; Refugee Scholars -- Poland; Medical research; Public health
- General Correspondence, 1981; 0.56 Cubic Feet 42 microfilm reels (35mm); 42 Reels 42 microfilm reels (35mm)
  Appraisal note
  The archival material has been reformatted and the original records are no longer available. User copies of the microfilm are available for access.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
  - International, 1981; 1981/100
    - Anderson, Bernard E., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 1)
    - Antoine, Pierre P., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 6)
    - Arbab, Farzam, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 65)
    - Barnish, Guy, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 69)
    - Bartholomew, Richard K., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 72)
    - Beasley, Marion G., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 77)
    - Bonman, John Michael, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 90)
    - Borlaug, Norman E., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 113)
    - Bowers, John Z., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 124)
    - Bruer, John T., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 127)
    - Cahn, Steven M., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 135)
    - Campbell, David R., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 138)
    - Celli, Roberto, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 149)
    - Coleman, James S., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 152)
    - Colton, Joel, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 183)
    - Court, David, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 229)
    - Crowder, Loy V., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 238)
    - Cummings, Ralph W., Jr., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 306)
    - Dapice, David O., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 609)
    - Davidson, Ralph K., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 637)
    - Deagle, Edwin A., Jr., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 640)
    - Douglas, Johnson E., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 643)
    - Edmundson, Kathryn Louise, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 692)
    - Elliot, Howard J.C., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 694)
    - Ember, George, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 699)
    - Garrity, Dennis P., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 708)
    - Gasbarre, Louis C., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 777)
    - Goffman, William, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 790)
    - Gossage, Wayne, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 795)
    - Grant, Ulysses J., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 798)
    - Gray, Clarence C. III, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 818)
    - Greenberg, Bernard G., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 824)
    - Hanson, Haldore, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 855)
    - Harrar, J. George, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 860)
    - Harris, P., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 871)
    - Harwood, Roland E., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 873)
    - Heaton, Herbert, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 876)
    - Hopkins, Kevin D., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 878)
    - House, Leland R., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 945)
    - Howe, Charles W., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 958)
    - Huddleston, Barbara, 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 966)
    - Jackson, Ben R., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 1132)
    - Jennings, Peter R., 1981 (Reel 1, Frame 1148)
    - Johnson, Loyd, 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 1)
    - Jonston, James E., 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 80)
    - Jordan, Peter, 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 141)
    - Klein, Pat, 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 146)
    - Laird, Reggie J., 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 149)
    - Lavine, Steven David, 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 202)
    - Lipkin, Mack, Jr., 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 204)
    - Lyle, Katherine Ch'iu, 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 209)
    - Lyman, Judith M., 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 229)
    - Lyman, Richard W. (Recommendations), 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 264)
    - Lyman, Richard W. (Southeast Asia Trip), 1981 (Reel 2, Frame 749)
    - Lyman, Richard W. (Speeches), 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 1)
    - Lyman, Richard W. (January), 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 135)
    - Lyman, Richard W. (February-June), 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 310)
    - Lyman, Richard W. (July-December), 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 535)
    - Maner, Jerome H., 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 858)
    - Mann, Charles K., 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 877)
    - Martinez, Eduardo, 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 960)
    - Martinez S., Eugenio, 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 965)
    - Martinez Gutierrez, Mario A., 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 979)
    - McCarthy, Kathleen D., 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 988)
    - McIntyre, Ian, 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 999)
    - McKelvey, John J., Jr., 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 1037)
    - McLean, Sheila A., 1981 (Reel 3, Frame 1045)
    - McPherson, Malcolm F., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 1)
    - Mock, Christopher Alden, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 78)
    - Moock, Joyce L., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 120)
    - Moomaw, James C., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 128)
    - Osby, William J., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 130)
    - Oshima, Harry T., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 134)
    - Osler, Robert D., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 137)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 145)
    - Pino, John A., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 150)
    - Posner, Joshua L., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 211)
    - Prentice, Michael A., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 246)
    - Rachie, Kenneth O., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 256)
    - Ratigan, Patricia, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 393)
    - Renfro, Bobby L., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 395)
    - Richardson, Malcolm L., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 437)
    - Robinson, Nan S., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 440)
    - Rohde, Jon E., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 452)
    - Sar, Marcin, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 457)
    - Scott, Virgil C., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 465)
    - Sechler, Susan Elizabeth, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 468)
    - Segal, Sheldon D., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 476)
    - Smeltzer, Dale G., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 481)
    - Smith, Herbert L., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 515)
    - Sonis, Abraam, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 519)
    - Spain, James M., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 531)
    - Sprague, Ernest W., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 567)
    - Stewart, Michael M., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 603)
    - Stifel, Laurence D., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 616)
    - Suchart, Upatham, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 645)
    - Suhrke, Astri, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 663)
    - Thompson, Anson E., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 686)
    - Tillman, Allen D., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 701)
    - Walsh, Julia A., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 726)
    - Warren, Kenneth S., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 729)
    - Warwick, Everett J., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 834)
    - Waugh, Robert K., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 846)
    - Wellhausen, Edwin J., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 1045)
    - White, Kerr L., 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 1103)
    - Woolf, Patricia, 1981 (Reel 4, Frame 1115)
    - Wortman, L. Sterling, 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 1)
    - Wright, Bill C., 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 278)
    - Yang, Rong-Rong, 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 280)
    - Young, William R., 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 283)
  - Administration, 1981/101
    - Administration - General, 1981; 1981/101.07
      - B-W, 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 317)
    - Applications for Employment - Visiting Research Fellows and Post-Doctorals (Dropped Post-Doc — E Under Countries), 1981; 1981/101.13
      - B-S, 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 339)
  - International Organizations, 1981; 1981/103
    - International Council for Research in Agroforestry (Conference), 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 384)
    - International (B-G), 1981 (Reel 5, Frame 478)
    - International (I-S), 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 1)
    - United Nations (D-W), 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 353)
    - United Nations Development Programme (G-M), 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 617)
    - United Nations Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization (Tanguiane, S.), 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 746)
    - United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund (Jolly, Richard), 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 805)
    - United Nations University (J-W), 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 838)
    - A-G, 1981 (Reel 6, Frame 982)
    - I-N, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 1)
    - W, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 272)
  - International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT), 1981; 1981/105
    - Economics, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 386)
  - Bellagio Study and Conference Center, 1981; 1981/120
    - Mendels, Franklin, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 411)
    - B-W, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 458)
  - Conflict in International Relations, Declinations, 1981; 1981/155
    - E-P, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 889)
  - Equal Opportunity - Basic Rights/Policy Research, 1981/175
    - Equal Opportunity - Basic Rights/Policy Research - Fellowships, 1981; 1981/175.E
      Fellowships
      - H-P, 1981 (Reel 7, Frame 921)
  - United States, 1981; 1981/200
    United States
    - Ac-Af, 1981 (Reel 8, Frame 1)
    - Agricultural Development Council (H-S), 1981 (Reel 8, Frame 179)
    - Ag-Al, 1981 (Reel 8, Frame 318)
    - American (A-C), 1981 (Reel 8, Frame 443)
    - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research (Woodson, Robert L.), 1981 (Reel 8, Frame 656)
    - American (E-F), 1981 (Reel 8, Frame 827)
    - American Home Economics (Strow, Helen), 1981 (Reel 9, Frame 1)
    - American Political Science Association, 1981 (Reel 9, Frame 280)
    - American (H-V), 1981 (Reel 9, Frame 363)
    - An-Ar, 1981 (Reel 9, Frame 654)
    - Asia Society, 1981 (Reel 9, Frame 817)
    - Atlantic Council (Military Service), 1981 (Reel 9, Frame 901)
    - As-Au, 1981 (Reel 10, Frame 1)
    - Barnes-McConnell, Pat, 1981 (Reel 10, Frame 341)
    - Ba-Be, 1981 (Reel 11, Frame 1)
    - Bi-Bl, 1981 (Reel 11, Frame 173)
    - Boston Women's Health Book Collective (Norsigian, Judy), 1981 (Reel 11, Frame 370)
    - Brown University (People's Ideology), 1981 (Reel 11, Frame 790)
    - Bo-Bv, 1981 (Reel 11, Frame 934)
    - Carnegie Foundation, 1981 (Reel 12, Frame 1)
    - Ca, 1981 (Reel 12, Frame 329)
    - Center for Applied Linguistics, 1981 (Reel 12, Frame 649)
    - Center for Community Change (National Citizen's Monitoring Project), 1981 (Reel 12, Frame 821)
    - Center for Public Resources (Pharmaceutical Conference), 1981 (Reel 13, Frame 1)
    - Center (E-P), 1981 (Reel 13, Frame 374)
    - City University of New York (A-W), 1981 (Reel 13, Frame 412)
    - Ce-Ci, 1981 (Reel 13, Frame 585)
    - Columbia University (A-W), 1981 (Reel 13, Frame 846)
    - Cornell Uiversity (B-Z), 1981 (Reel 14, Frame 1)
    - Council on Foundations (Goldberg, Linda Z.), 1981 (Reel 14, Frame 165)
    - Council for Opportunity in Graduate Management Education, 1981 (Reel 14, Frame 359)
    - Cl-Co, 1981 (Reel 14, Frame 558)
    - Cr, 1981 (Reel 15, Frame 1)
    - D-Di, 1981 (Reel 15, Frame 327)
    - Duke University (M-W), 1981 (Reel 15, Frame 570)
    - Do-Dy, 1981 (Reel 15, Frame 702)
    - Ea-Eh, 1981 (Reel 15, Frame 766)
    - El-Ev, 1981 (Reel 16, Frame 1)
    - Federation of Public Programs in the Humanities (Weiland, Steven), 1981 (Reel 16, Frame 681)
    - Federation of Southern Cooperatives (Emergency Support), 1981 (Reel 16, Frame 879)
    - Fa-Fe, 1981 (Reel 17, Frame 1)
    - Fisk University (J-S), 1981 (Reel 17, Frame 89)
    - Ford Foundation (B-H), 1981 (Reel 17, Frame 103)
    - Fi-Fo, 1981 (Reel 17, Frame 169)
    - Fr-Fu, 1981 (Reel 17, Frame 709)
    - Ga-Gi, 1981 (Reel 18, Frame 1)
    - Gr-Gu, 1981 (Reel 18, Frame 308)
    - Harvard University (Health Systems), 1981 (Reel 18, Frame 461)
    - Harvard University (A-S), 1981 (Reel 18, Frame 697)
    - Ha, 1981 (Reel 18, Frame 909)
    - He-Hi, 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 1)
    - Ho-Hy, 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 184)
    - Independent Film and Distribution Center, 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 329)
    - Institute for Cultural Progress (Ritterbush, Philip C.), 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 544)
    - Institute for Society, Ethics and the Life Sciences (Ethical Issues), 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 637)
    - Institute (A-S), 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 732)
    - International Analysis Center (Terrorism Proposal), 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 942)
    - International Analysis Center, Terrorism Proposal (Supplementary Material), 1981 (Reel 19, Frame 1143)
    - International (C-N), 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 1)
    - Iowa State University (T-W), 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 137)
    - I, 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 160)
    - Jobs for Youth-Boston, Inc.(Jungmann, Fredrick), 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 353)
    - J, 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 534)
    - K-Kh, 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 877)
    - Ki-Kr, 1981 (Reel 20, Frame 1159)
    - La, 1981 (Reel 21, Frame 1)
    - Le-Ll, 1981 (Reel 21, Frame 89)
    - Local Initiatives Support Corporation, 1981 (Reel 21, Frame 154)
    - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (Supplementary Material), 1981 (Reel 21, Frame 424)
    - Lo-Lu, 1981 (Reel 21, Frame 577)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (C-S), 1981 (Reel 21, Frame 804)
    - Ma, 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 1)
    - Mc, 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 157)
    - Me, 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 183)
    - Michigan State University (A-W), 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 337)
    - Montclair State College (Lipman, Matthew), 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 534)
    - Mi-My, 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 611)
    - National Academy of Sciences (G-V), 1981 (Reel 22, Frame 803)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (G-T), 1981 (Reel 23, Frame 1)
    - National (A-B), 1981 (Reel 23, Frame 115)
    - National Center for Education Statistics (Coleman, James), 1981 (Reel 23, Frame 314)
    - National Commission for Employment Policy, 1981 (Reel 23, Frame 480)
    - National Committee for Responsive Philanthropy, 1981 (Reel 23, Frame 715)
    - National Council on the Aging, 1981 (Reel 24, Frame 1)
    - National (C ), 1981 (Reel 24, Frame 132)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Lyman, Richard W. (January-February), 1981 (Reel 24, Frame 359)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Lyman, Richard W. (March-April), 1981 (Reel 24, Frame 775)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Lyman, Richard W. (May-June), 1981 (Reel 24, Frame 949)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Lyman, Richard W. (July-August), 1981 (Reel 25, Frame 1)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Lyman, Richard W. (September-November), 1981 (Reel 25, Frame 376)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (J-S), 1981 (Reel 25, Frame 480)
    - National (C-F), 1981 (Reel 25, Frame 605)
    - National Institute for Dispute Resolution, 1981 (Reel 25, Frame 917)
    - National (H-O), 1981 (Reel 26, Frame 1)